Uh, the way you crushed Mike at ping pong
was such a turn-on.
자기가 마이크를 이기는 걸 보니까 너무 흥분되던데
You want to...
어때..
You know, I, I'd love to but I'm a little tired.
하고 싶긴 한데, 좀 피곤하네
I'll put a pillow case over my head.
머리 안보이게 베게커버 쓸께
You're on.
어서누워!
Hey / What's up?
얘들아
왠일이야
Well, Ok, Mike's taking a shower,
which by the way, there is no law against.
응 마이크는 지금 샤워하고 있거든 법에 어긋나지도 않고
And then we're gonna grab some food
so if you want..
뭐 좀 먹으러 갈껀데 같이..
...(finally)...
Is that Ross?
이거 로스 목소리야?
응, 벽이 얇아서 다들려
Yeah, you can hear everything
through the stupid walls.
누구랑 같이 있는 것 같은데?
Sounds like he's with someone.
He could be alone. This morning I heard him
do push-ups and then talk to his triceps.
혼자인지도 몰라 오늘 아침엔 팔굽혀펴기하면서 자기 근육에다 대고 말을 하더라구
Wait a minute. I think Phoebe is right.
잠깐만, 피비가 맞는 것 같애
Yeah, I hear someone else in there with him.
다른 사람 소리가 들려
오우~
겔러 박사님
Dr. Geller.
God, you're amazing.
당신은 역시 멋져
그렇게 부르라고 말한 적도 없는데도 말야
I didn't even have to ask you to call me that.
Oh my God! That's Charlie!
세상에, 저거 찰리잖아!
She's cheating on Joey with Ross!
조이 몰래 로스랑 바람피고 있는거야?
Oh, that tart, floozy, Giant!
덩치만 큰 ..헤픈년.. 같으니라구
I'm not sure about this.
이러면 안될 것 같아
Yeah, you..you're right.
This is none of our business.
그래 니말이 맞어
우리가 상관할 일이 아니야
그게아니라, 이게 제일 잘 들을 수 있는
방법인지 모르겠다구
No, I'm not sure that is the best way
to hear everything. Someone get me a glass!
유리컵 좀 가져와봐!
난 관둘래
I'm not gonna do this, Ok?
I'm not gonna eavesdrop on my friend.
친구 사생활 엿듣는건 그만 둘래
(Oh, I love Barbados)
(..난 바베이도스가 너무 좋아..)
Oh, I can't believe I'm kissing you.
너하고 키스하고 있다니 믿어지지가 않아
I'm kissing Rachel!
내가 레이첼하고 키스하고 있다!
그래~
그 레이첼이 바로 나야~
I know! I'm her!
Rachel and Joey! It's Rachel and Joey!
레이첼하고 조이가!
뭐라구?
What?
빨리 와봐!
Get over here!
와우!
Whoa!
Oh my God! I love how thin these walls are!
세상에.. 벽이 얇아서 이렇게 좋다니~!
고마워
Thank you.
F.R.I.E.N.D.S
Transcribed by - Kevin Kim
You CAN distrubute this file freely without my permission.
1001. The One After
Joey and Rachel Kiss
So no one told you that was gonna be this way
[ 제 작 ]
코리아닷컴 프렌즈동호회 자막팀
대망의 10시즌 첫 자막이군요 ^^
Your job's a joke, you're broke,
Your love life's D.O.A.
자막팀의 동의 없이 수정/배포는 금합니다
It's like you're always stuck in 2nd gear.
자막에 대한 피드백은
동호회 게시판으로 해주십시요
When it hasn't been your day, your week,
your month, or even your year ....but
I'll be there for you.
when the rain starts to pour
Like I've been there before
I'll be there for you.
'Cause you're there for me...too.
Hey, you know, before, you said that nothing
could happen between us. What changed?
있잖아.. 전에 우리사이는 안된다고 했었잖아.
왜 맘이 변한거야?
로스때문에 그랬던거지
Well, I only said that because of Ross
and then I saw him kissing Charlie.
그런데 로스가 찰리한테 키스하는 걸 보고나니
What?
뭐라고?
로스하고 찰리가?
Ross and Charlie?
와, 이 사람 저 사람 바꿔가며 만나는거야?
Wow! She's really making her way
through the group, huh?
Eh, who am I to talk?
뭐, 내가 그런 얘기 할 입장은 아니지
I can't believe this. Rachel and Joey?
정말 믿을 수가 없어
레이첼하고 조이가 저러다니
How about the dinosaur twins in the other room?
저쪽방에 공룡쟁이들은 어떻고?
No one is manning that wall.
저쪽이 비었잖아!
I'm on it!
내가 맡을께!
Anything?
뭐가 들려?
I think I hear curtain's closing.
커튼을 닫고 있어
We've got shoes being kicked off over here.
얘네들은 신발을 벗어던지고 있어
침대 스프링 소리야 확실해
bed springs! Unmistakable!
You do realize that's your brother.
너 지금 네 오빠가 그러는 걸 듣고 있는거 알어?
Not until you said it. Somebody switch!
니가 말할떄까지 몰랐어
바꿔줘!
잠깐만
Wait a minute! Ross and Charlie. Joey and Rachel.
로스하고 찰리..
조이하고 레이첼..
피비하고 마이크..
Phoebe and Mike. We're the only people
leaving with the same person we came with.
우리만 처음 같이 온 사람하고 있는 거잖아
That's not true. I came with Monica
and I'm leaving with 'Weird Al'.
아닌것 같은데.
난 올때 모니카랑 같이 왔는데
이상한 L자 모양이랑 집에 가게 됐잖아
머리 얘긴 그만해
Ok, I've had it with the hair jokes.
Tomorrow morning before we leave,
I'm going to the salon.
내일 떠나기 전에 미장원 갔다 올께
알았어! 이 시끄러운 잡초야!
Ok, buckwheat.
You, you got to hear this. It's great!
It's, it's like free porn.
너네들 와서 이것좀 들어라
공짜 포르노가 따로 없어
왜 그래?
Is everything ok?
Yeah, it's just I...I don't think I can do this.
못하겠어
Oh, is it because of what might be under bed spread
침대보에 뭐가 있을것 같아서 그래?
cause I saw that news report too
with that infrared and we could just...
나도 적외선으로 실험한 뉴스 봤거든.
그럼 옮기자..
No, no, no, no, uh,
아냐 그게 아니야
Look, I, I need to talk to Joey.
먼저 조이한테 얘기해야 할 것 같애
I mean you guys just broke up.
둘이 헤어진지도 얼마 안됬잖아
Before anything more happens between us,
I need to know he's okay with it.
더 진도가 나가기 전에
조이가 어떻게 받아들일지 물어봐야겠어
I...I completely understand.
나도 이해해
Alright, I'm gonna go find him.
가서 조이를 찾아볼께
I just need a, need a second
before I can...you know
잠깐만.. 거기 흥분좀 가라앉히고..
Grandma, grandma,
할머니.. 할머니.. 할머니..
됐어 이따가 봐
/ 그래
Okay, I'll see you later. / Ok
That's the door. He's gone.
문소리야 로스가 나갔어
And she's turning on the TV,
찰리는..
티비를 켜고..
and watching ...
'Miss congeniality'!
'미스 에이전트'를 보네
Honey, if you know it through a wall,
you know it too well!
소리만 듣고 알았다면 너무 심한 거야
뭐하고 있는거야?
Hey, what are you guys doing?
Ah,..we're, we're just sad to go
so we're just saying good bye to the hotel.
떠나려니까 너무 슬퍼서 호텔한테 작별인사 하고 있는거야
I love you.
사랑해..
Paradise hotel. Golf resort and spa.
..파라다이스호텔, 골프 리조트랑 사우나야..
Yeah, we had a great time. Thank you.
너무 즐거웠어 고마워
잘있어
Bye.
Okay. Um, hey, have you guys seen Joey anywhere?
그래.. 혹시 조이 못봤어?
자기 여자친구 찰리랑 방에 있겠지뭐
He's probably in his room
with his current girlfriend Charlie.
That's the situation as we know it.
우린 그렇게 알고 있어
조이 보면 내가 찾고 있다고 말해줄래?
Well, if you see him, could you please
tell him I'm looking for him?
You got it! / Thanks
알았어
/ 고마워
Thank you.
고마워
Other wall, people, other wall!
이쪽벽이 남았잖아! 이쪽벽!
Rach, you there?
레이첼! 안에 있어?
Oh my God! It's Ross. What are we gonna do?
로스잖아! 어떡하지?
Ok, just , just, be calm, just be calm
for all I know is
진정하고, 진정하고. 그냥 놀고 있던 척해
we're just, we're just hanging out together.
Alright, let's just be nonchalant.
태연하자구!
그건 태연한게 아니잖아!
That's not nonchalant!
No idea what it means!
태연하다는게 무슨 뜻인지 모르겠어
Oh!
Ok, just hide.
얼른 숨기나 해
레이첼?
/ 잠깐만
Rach? / Coming.
침대밑으로 들어가
Try under the bed. Try under the bed.
There's no room under the bed.
침대 밑에 자리가 없어
별일 없는거야?
Is everything okay?
응
Yeah.
Hey / Hi
안녕
Do you know where Joey is?
조이 어디있는줄 알아?
'정말' 모르겠는데
I really don't.
잠깐 얘기 좀 할까?
/ 응 그럼
Can I talk to you for a minute?
Yeah sure.
I don't believe this!
세상에..
Have you guys been...? / Shhh.
너네 계속 듣고..
쉿! 여긴 듣는 쪽이야
This is the listening side of the wall.
And then she told me that
she and Joey had broken up, and that
그러더니 조이랑 헤어졌다고 하더라고
part of the reason was that
she had feelings for me.
나한테 마음이 있기도 해서 그렇게 된거래
Uh-huh. Right. Yeah.
으응 그래
나도 찰리 처음 만났을때 데이트 신청하려고 했었잖아
And you know I wanted to ask Charlie out
since the day I met her.
Oh, I know! I know it's been really hard for you.
알아. 정말 힘들었을거야
Anyway, one thing led to another, and
어쨌거나 그러다가
우리도 모르게 키스해 버렸어
before you know it, we, we were kissing.
I mean how, how angry do you think
Joey's gonna be.
조이가 얼마나 화낼 꺼 같애?
모르겠는데. 정말 모르겠어
That is hard to say, Ross. That is hard to say.
You know, I've got to go find him.
He's got to be here some place.
조이를 찾아봐야겠어
여기 어딘가 있을꺼야
You would think!
너도 그렇게 생각하지?!
조이!
Joey!
로스 갔어?
Is he gone?
How are you doing this?
대체 어딨는 거야!
어.. 이게 뭐야
wh..what? Hey!
What are you...what is this?
Have you guys been listening this entire time?
너네 계속 듣고 있었던 거야?
물론이지~!
Yeah!
Now but what is this?
너네들은 뭐야
뭐냐고? 어디보자. 10분동안 키스하고나서 친구들한테 얘기하고 있으니
What is this? Well, let's see.
We, we kissed for 10 minutes and
now we're talking to our friends about it
so I guess this is the sixth grade!
완전 국민학교 6학년 꼴 인거지
No, no. Have you thought about
how complicated this could get?
이일이 얼마나 복잡해질지 생각해봤어?
What about Ross?
로스는 어떡해?
Well, he's with Charlie now.
찰리랑 잘되가잖아
Yeah, but he wants to talk to you
before anything really happens with her.
그렇긴 해도, 더 나아가기전에 너한테 얘기하려고 하고 있단 말야
and as his friend I mean don't you think
he deserves the same from you?
친구로서, 너도 그래야 된다고 생각하지 않아?
You're a pain in my ass, Geller.
성가시게 구는군.. 갤러양!
알았어 너네들 충고는 고마운데
이건 조이랑 나 사이의 문제니까
Alright, look, you guys, look.
We appreciate all the advice but this is between Joey and me,
and I think we can handle it.
우리둘이 해결할께
/ 좋아, 돌아갈께
Ok, while we go back in there, but
will you do one thing for us,
하지만 너희들을 걱정하는
우리를 위해 한가지만 해줄래?
the people that care about you? / Sure.
물론
/ 발음을 똑똑히 해줘!
Enunciate!
나가
Get out!
쟤네들이 맞는 건가?
Are they right?
Probably, yeah.
아마도 그렇겠지
I mean, maybe we should ...
잠깐 멈추고 로스한테 얘기해야 할 것 같애
hold off until we talk to Ross.
그래, 맞아
Yeah, yeah. We can wait.
We don't have to do anything tonight.
기다리지뭐 오늘밤 당장 뭐할 것도 아니고
Yeah, I think, I think that would be best.
그게 최선일 것 같애
그만 가볼께
So, so I'm gonna, I'm gonna take off.
although...
그래도
/ 난 "그래도"가 좋더라
I like although!
I mean, you know.
로스하고 난 데이트 안한지가 6년이나 됬는걸
Ross and I haven't dated in like...
six years?
6년이나?
6 years?
와우.. 거의 중고등학교 합친만큼 오래됬네
Wow! It's almost as long as high school.
게다가 지금 찰리랑 잘되고 있고
Plus, you know he is ...with Charlie, you know.
Absolutely!
맞아 널 생각하고 있진 않아
/ 아니지
He's not thinking about you. / No!
I'm thinking about you.
난 널 생각하고 있어
Yeah.
그래
로스는 잊자
Let's forget about Ross.
He's forgotten.
벌써 잊었어
Waht's wrong?
왜그래?
Nothing.
아무것도 아냐
진짜 왜그래?
Seriously, what is it?
Nothing. It's really...it's nothing.
Come here. Come here.
아냐. 진짜 아무것도 아냐
왜그러는데?
What's wrong?
Uh, sorry, I just...um,
미안해...
..로스가 계속 생각나
I can't seem to get Ross out of my head.
Well, maybe I can help.
내가 도와줄께
Ah, your lips are so soft. Do that again?
니 입술은 너무 부드러워 또 해줘
-Yeah, we, we need to tak to Ross. Yeah.
-Yeah.
아무래도 로스한테 먼저 얘기해야겠다
Hey / Hey
안녕
준비 다 됬어?
You guys are ready to go?
Not quite. Monica's still at the salon
and I'm just finishing packing.
아직. 모니카는 미용실 갔고 난 짐싸는 중이야
Dude! You're not taking your bible?
야, 성경책 안가져가?
You're not supposed to take that.
그거 가져가면 안되잖아
Besides, it's new testament.
What are you gonna do with it?
게다가 신약 성서잖아
뭐하려고?
Learn about Jesus.
예수에 대해 배워야지
Hey / So... did you talk to Joey?
안녕
조이한테 얘기했어?
Oh no, no. I couldn't find him.
아니 아직. 조이를 못찾았어
I'm just gonna talk to him on the plane.
비행기에서 얘기하려고
Okay, sounds like a good idea.
잘 생각했어.
Dr. Geller.
갤러 박사님~
그만해
Stop it.
P...h... D.
박.사.니임~
You're filthy.
넌 정말 화끈하다니까
너네 모니카 봤어?
Hey, have you guys seen Monica?
Uh, actually I think she went to the salon.
미용실 갔다던데
그래 맞아 미용실 갔지
Oh, yeah, oh, she went to the salon, alright.
Check it out!
나좀 봐라~
Whose day just got better?
너무 멋져졌지?
Chandler!
챈들러!!
Hey. Ahhh....
왔어? 허걱!
What do you think?
어때~?
어떠냐구?
I think... I think I can see your scalp.
머,머릿가죽이 보이는 것 같은데?
Don't you just love it?
너무 좋지 않아?
Yeah, yeah.
You've got shellfish in your head.
그,그래..
머리에 온통 조개잖아
It's, uh..., it's something.
뭐 같다야. 잘했어. 우리 이쁜이..
You go girlfriend!
You've never said that in your life, have you?
여자한테 '이쁜이'라고 말한거 처음이지?
Not once. / I thought so.
태어나서 처음이야
/ 그럴줄 알았어
And listen to this.
이거좀 들어봐~
대단한데!
볼 거리만 있는 게 아니고 들을 거리도 있구만
What do you know? It's a treat for the eyes
... and the ears!
이런.. 깨지고 나서 옆에 앉기가 좀 그렇네
Wow, it's uh...,
it's kinda weird I'm sitting next to Charlie
after we broke up.
Yeah, it's almost as if Air Barbados
doesn't care about your social life.
그래 바베이도스가 너의 사회생활에는
신경써주지 않는 것 같네
Look, does someone mind
switching to sit with Charlie?
나랑 자리 좀 바꿔줄래?
Oh, I, I mean, I, dude, I spent
the whole conference with Charlie.
난 찰리랑 학회 내내 같이 있었는걸
I understand.
그렇겠다
/ 아냐 내가 바꿔줄께
No, I'll do it.
Wish I could switch with someone.
나야말로 누가 자리좀 바꿔줬으면 좋겠는데
I really don't want to sit with
Allen Iverson over there.
앨런 아이버스랑 앉기 정말 싫은데
[앨런 아이버스 :
NBA농구선수. 모니카의 머리스타일을 하고 있음]
Um, you know once we're in the air,
공중에 뜨고, 안전벨트 풀러도 된다고 하면
and the captain turns off the seatbelt sign,
you feel free to roam about my cabin.
내 자리에서 맘대로 놀아
And you should be careful
when checking your overhead bins.
하지만 머리위의 선반은 조심해야 될껄
cause items may shift during the...
물건들이 움직일수도..
Aw, you're not good at this.
아, 넌 그런 스타일로 얘기 안해도 돼
You don't have to go home tonight, do you?
오늘 집에 안가도 되지?
No, I think I can come over. Saturday, right?
응 너네 집으로 가자. 토요일이잖아
Oh, / What?
앗
왜?
Um, I can't, I can't do anything tonight.
오늘은 안돼
Why not?
왜?
I have a date.
데이트가 있어
You have a date?
데이트라고? 누구랑?
With who?
Oh, it's... my girlfriend.
여자친구랑
You have, you have a girlfriend?
너 여자친구있어?
Yeah, ...when you and I broke up,
I started seeing someone.
응 너랑 헤어지고나서 다른 사람 만났어
Whoa, for how long?
얼마나 됬어?
3 months. / 3 months?
석달
석달이나?
좋아
Ok.
This is probably none of my business but
how long do you think you're gonna keep seeing her?
내가 상관할 바는 아니지만 얼마나 더 만날껀데?
I'll tell her that it's over tonight at dinner.
오늘 저녁에 만나서 그만 만나자고 얘기할께 약속해
I ...I promise.
알았어 그렇게해
Oh, okay, good. You do that.
And then when you get home, maybe there'll
be a special delivery package waiting for you.
그러고나서 집에오면 특별 패키지가 배달되서 널 기다리고 있을거야
좋아 내가 사인해주지
Maybe I'll sign for it.
Tear it open.
Pull out the packing material.
그리고 포장지를 찢은 다음에..
You know what? We're gonna have sex.
Let's just leave it there.
그냥 섹스한다고 하자
Alright, I'm gonna go talk to Joey.
I think this is the right time.
지금 조이한테 가서 얘기하는게 좋을 것 같아
He's always in a good mood
after the flight attendant says "duty free".
승무원이 '응가 꽁짜(doody free)'라고
말하는 걸 듣고나면 항상 기분이 좋아지거든..
['duty free(면세점)'와 발음혼동]
Okay, good luck.
그래.. 행운을 빌어
Ross's coming over. I think
now will be a really good time to talk to him.
로스가 오고 있어 지금 말하는게 좋을 것 같아
Oh, oh, I guess so. I'm just really nervous.
그럴 것 같애. 좀 떨려서 그래
Ok, well, keep in mind that by the time you're done,
they'll probably be serving dinner.
알았어 니가 그말을 하고 나면 저녁이 나올꺼라는 것만 기억해
오
Ooh...
Still nervous?
그래도 떨려?
난 라자냐 먹을래
I'm gonna get the lasagna.
레이첼..
Hey, Rach. / Yeah.
Do you... do you mind if I sit here for a sec?
자리 잠깐만 비켜줄 수 있어?
Yeah. yeah, sure. Yeah.
물론이야
헤이
Hey. / Hey.
So I, um, I kinda need to talk to you about Charlie.
저기..
찰리에 대해서 너한테 할말이 있어
Yeah?
그래?
Ok, last night, after you guys broke up,
어제 너네가 깨지고 나서말야..
so sorry to hear about that by the way,
그거 정말 정말 유감이야
well, Charlie and I were talking and ...well
찰리랑 얘기를 했어 그리고..
키스했지?
You kissed.
What? ...What?
뭐,뭐,뭐라고?
왜, 왜, 왜 그렇게 생각해?
What would give you that idea?
I saw you.
봤으니까
Yeah, we kissed
그래 키스했어
하지만 그것뿐이었어
but nothing else nothing else happened, okay?
Ross, Ross, it's okay. / What?
로스 괜찮아
뭐라고?
It's okay.
괜찮다구
I totally understand now you guys make
way more sense than her and I ever did.
다 이해할 수 있다구
나보다 너가 훨씬 더 잘 어울려
You know? And...
잘됬으면 좋겠어
I want you to be happy.
정말?
Are you serious?
Yeah.
그럼
근데 나도 할말이..
Now I have something....
I AM speechless!
정말 할말을 잃게 만드는구나
무엇보다 나의 행복을 바란다니..
I mean the fact that you would
put my happiness first like that?
I mean you....you are an incredible friend,
you know that?
넌 정말 좋은 친구야 알아?
그러기 전에
Look before you go to...
No, no, I mean it.
아냐 진심이야 너 정말 멋지고..
I mean you're so , you're so loyal man. and, and
selfless and generous.
욕심 없고..
관대해
좀 그렇지
I am those things, yeah.
You know, I've known Chandler longer
so I always think of him as my best friend.
더 오래전부터 친구여서 첸들러를
가장 친한 친구라고 생각했었는데..
But now...
..다시 생각해봐야겠어
I may have to rethink some stuff.
너 정말..
Dude!
Hey, if there is ever anything
I can do for you.
내가 너한테 뭔가 해줄 수 있는게 없을까
I can't think of anything.
아무것도 없을 것 같은데
Thanks. / Yeah.
So hi / Hi
So you, uh,..you talked to Joey.
조이랑 얘기 다 된거야?
Oh yeah. We had a really good talk.
응 물론 잘됬어
Oh, that's great! / Yeah.
다행이다 정말 괜찮은거지?
Oh so everything's okay?
Oh, no, no. It's great! It's great!
괜찮다니깐 조이는 정말 괜찮은 애야
He, he's an amazing guy.
Oh,...well, obviously I think so too.
나도 그렇게 생각해
Well, I'm, I'm so excited about this.
나도 흥분된다니깐
Really? Excited?
정말? 흥분된다고?
Oh, what? Are you kidding?
진짜라니깐
I have had some very dirty dreams about this.
찐한 꿈도 꿨는걸
Excuse me.
잠깐만
You didn't tell him, did you?
너 얘기 안했지, 그지?!
못했어 계속 나에관해서 좋게 얘기해서 화나게 할수가 없었다구
I couldn't. He was saying
all these really nice things about me.
되돌리기 싫었단말야
내가 챈들러보다 좋다고 했다니깐
I didn't want him to get mad
and take'em all back.
I'm gonna edge out Chandler. / Oh God!
Alright, fine. You know what? Joey, forget it.
좋아 알았어
When we go back to New York, I will tell him.
뉴욕에 돌아가면 내가 얘기할래
고마워 그래주면 고맙지
Thank you, yeah. I appreciate that.
Hi, Mike's place.
여보세요 마이크네 집입니다
Hey, it's Mike.
나야
Ooh, that was fast!
벌써 끝냈어?
Oh, ah, no, she's not here yet.
(아냐 아직 안왔어)
You know, I think I'm gonna just take off
and break up with her over the phone.
그냥 나가서 전화로 끝내는게 나을 것 같아
No, you can't do that!
그러면 안돼 마이크
Oh, come on, Mike. strap on a pair.
확실하게 해치우라구!
Why don't you just tell her
that we got back together?
그냥 우리 다시 화해했다고 하면 어때?
You know, women appreciate honesty.
여자는 솔직한 걸 좋아한다구
또 가끔은..
We also... appreciate gentle spanking
once in a while . Just FYI.
..엉덩이를 살짝 때리면서 하는 것도 좋아하고
One more thing. There might be a picture of
"Precious" on my coffee table.
그리고 거기 커피테이블에 "귀염둥이" 사진이 있을거야
Her name's Precious?
그 아가씨 이름이 "귀염둥이"이야?
Is she a pure breed or
did you pick her up at the pound?
순종이야 아니면 그냥 아무데서나 얻은거야?
(그냥 말해주는거야)
Anyway, I just want to give you a heads up.
Okay. Oh, and you know if she gets upset,
만약 그녀가 화내면 배를 긁어주고 토닥토닥 해줘
just scratch her tummy and give her Liva snap.
안녕하세요 전 '귀염둥이'라고 하는데요 누구시죠?
Hi, I'm Precious. Who are you?
전 피비라고 하는데요
I'm, I'm Phoebe.
피비?
Phoebe? Mike's ex-girlfriend Phoebe?
마이크가 진짜 사랑한 옛날 여자친구 피비 말인가요?
The love of his life? That Phoebe?
Enchante'e.
처음 뵙겠습니다
Oh, I can't wait for everyone at work to see these! Ow!
직장사람들한테 이 머리 빨리 보여주고 싶어 죽겠어
-You go back to work tomorrow night, right?
-Yeah
내일 저녁부터 일하러 가는 거지?
/ 그래
사람들한테 그걸 보여준다는 말은 아침에 그걸 풀지 않겠다는거야?
So if you want people to see them,
then by definition
you're not having them taken out,
say at the break of dawn?
Well, if I had them taken out then
I wouldn't be able to do this.
이걸 풀면 이렇게 못해주잖아
좋지 그지?
You like that, right?
What are you singing?
무슨 노랠 하는거야?
It's Bolero from "10".
"10"에 나온 무용곡이잖아
It's "ride of the Valkyrie's"
from apocalypse now.
"지옥의 묵시록"에 나온 "Ride of the valkiries"라구
See, here's the thing. The corn rows are
really a solution for your frizzy hair problem.
이게 니 골치아픈 곱슬머리를 진정시키기는 했어
And now that we're at home
you don't have that problem any more.
하지만 이젠 집에 왔으니까 문제 없잖아
So if you think about it, I HATE them.
그래서 말인데 머리 정말 너무 이상해
What? You said you liked them.
맘에 든다고 했었잖아
Did I? Let's refresh.
내가? 잘 생각해봐
I believe what I said was
that I could see your scalp.
네 머릿가죽이 보인다고 말했던 것 같은데
Fine, so you don't like them.
Everybody else does.
넌 맘에 안든다 이거지? 다른 사람들은 다 좋아해
또 다시 기억해봐
Again, let's journey back.
As I recall, what Rachel said was
she had never noticed the shape of your skull before.
레이첼은 네 두개골 모양 처음봤다고 그러지 않았었어?
and Joey...
조이는..
well, Joey didn't realize
there was anything different.
..뭐가 바꼈는지도 몰랐고
알았어 어쨌든 상관없어
You know what? I don't care.
I like it like this, and I'm gonna keep it.
난 이게 맘에 들어. 이렇게 놔둘꺼야
And you're just jealous
because your hair can't do this.
이렇게 못하니까 질투하는거지?
아야
Ouch!
이에 꼈어?
Get yourself in the tooth?
And the eye!
눈에도!
Hi, there she is . Hi, Emma. Oh my God.
안녕 우리애기 왔네
안녕 에마
I missed you. Oh, Emma,
I missed you so much.
보고싶었어 에마야 너무너무
Did you have a good time
with grandma Greene? Huh?
그린 할머니랑 잘 놀았어?
할머니가 또 장난감으로 항우울제를 줬니?
Did she give you a bottle of
antidepressants again to use as a rattle?
그거 딱 한번뿐이었어 로스
That was one time, Ross and
they were only like 5 milligrams.
겨우 5mg이었다고
Ooh, hey, Emma,
Daddy has some presents for you, okay? okay?
아빠가 선물 사왔단다
여기서 잠깐만 기다리렴
I want you to wait right here.
Come here, sweetie.
자 아가야
로스.. 사실 너한테 꼭 해야할 말이 있어
Huh, Ross,um actually there is something
that I really need to talk to you about.
Ok, shoot.
그래? 뭔데?
음..뭐냐면
Okay, um, alright, here's the deal.
Oh, no!
안돼!
What? What is it?
왜그래
Oh, major shampoo explosion!
샴푸가 터졌어
Ah, look, Ross, this really isn't easy.
말하기 쉽진 않은데
Oh, it's all over everything.
아주 삼푸바다구만!
Why? Why me?
왜, 왜 저에게 이런 고통을 주시나이까?
Because you took 300 bottles of shampoo?
샴푸를 3병이나 가져왔으니까 그렇지
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. You were saying?
미안 미안
말하던거 계속해봐
Well, yeah, ok, it's about me and...
응 그래 이건 내문제인데
세상에 이것도 터졌어
Oh, not another one!
이런 이건 로션이잖아
Oh my God! Oh and this is moisturizer.
It's even harder to clean!
닦아내기도 힘든데
왜 착하게 살아온 나한테 이런 일이 생기냐구!
Why? Why do bad things happen to good people?
Wow, well, clearly this is not a good time.
지금은 때가 아닌것 같네
그걸 말이라고 해?!
Don't you think?
그래 끊어
Okay, bye.
Alright so Mike's... on his way over.
이리로 온대요
You thought you guys were meeting here and
he thought you were meeting at the restaurant.
당신은 여기서 만난다고 생각했고
마이크는 레스토랑에서 만나는 줄 알았고
So you know ...doesn't really matter
who's right or wrong.
누가 맞느냐는 중요하지 않죠
The point is... I'm gonna take off.
저는 이만 갈께요
Wait a minute. I'm not letting you leave
until you tell me what's going on here.
당신한테 듣고 싶진 않지만
I mean, are you guys
getting back together or something?
혹시 다시 만나게 된건가요?
Alright.
Susie, can I call you Susie?
수지씨, 수지씨라고 불러도 될까요?
My name is Precious.
제 이름은 "귀염둥이"인데요
I can't say that.
제가 그렇게 부르긴 힘들죠
Um, Susie, I'm gonna be straight with you.
돌리지 않고 말할께요
마이크랑 다시 사귀기로 했어요
Mike and I are back together
and um unfortunately that effectively ends
your relationship with him.
그러니까.. 당신과 마이크의 관계는..
끝난거구요
And he's very sorry about that and wishes you
the best of luck in all your endeavors.
당신과 마이크의 관계에 대해서
그는 아주 미안해 하고 있고
행운을 빌어줄 거에요
I just can't believe this.
믿어지지가 않아요
Why?
왜 도대체 왜 나한테 이러는 거죠?
Well, I don't ...
Why would he do this?
I mean what's wrong with me?
내가 뭘 잘못했길래
Nothing. There's nothing wrong with you.
당신은 아무 잘못 없어요
내 말은 난 어떡해야 하냐구요!
I don't know what the hell am I supposed to do now!
Damn it, woman. Pull yourself together!
젠장. 정신차려요!
자신감을 가지라구요!
Have some pride for the love of God!
Ok, not a fan of the tough love.
터프한 방식은 안 통하는군요
I just can't believe that
Mike didn't give me any warning.
믿을 수가 없어요
마이크는 아무말도 안했었다구요
But he didn't really know.
그도 몰랐었어요
You know, he wasn't planning on
coming to Barbados and proposing to me.
바베이도스에 와서 나한테 청혼하려고 계획했던건 아니었어요
He proposed to you?
당신한테 청혼했다구요?
This is the worst birthday ever!
내 생애 최악의 생일이야
Look,... Precious.
이것 봐요..
"귀염둥이"씨..
마이크는 당신만큼 괜찮지 않아요
Mike's not worth this.
You're an attractive, intelligent woman and
당신은 매력적이고 지적인데
let's face it. Mike's kind of a Wang.
마이크는 뭐라고 할까 좀 모자라잖아요
I mean he proposed to me
while he was still seeing you.
당신을 만나는 중에 나한테 청혼을 하고
He was gonna break up with you on your birthday?
당신 생일날 헤어지려고 하고
And I don't like to kiss and tell
but he cheated on you a lot this weekend.
비밀인데
이번 주말에 어떤 여자랑 엄청 해댔다구요
Oh my God. You know, maybe you're right!
세상에. 당신 말이 맞는 지도 몰라요
Maybe I don't need him.
그가 필요없을 지도 몰라요
I deserve to be treated with respect.
날 존경해주는 사람을 만나야죠
Screw you, Mike. You're a coward and a bastard
and I hope you rot in hell.
뒈져 버려 마이크
겁장이 나쁜놈!
지옥에나 가버려
You're welcome.
고맙지?
Honey, you've been in there for a long time.
Is everything okay?
자기야 너무 오래 있는거 아냐
괜찮은 거지?
Not really.
그다지
I have a problem.
문제가 생겼어
그래? 뭔데
Really?
What happened?
Well..., I was dancing around and
singing "no woman, no cry"
춤추면서 "No woman no cry"를 부르고 있었는데
and... I got stuck.
머리카락이 껴버렸어
못 움직이겠어?
You can't move at all?
Oh, I can move.
움직일 수야 있지
If I entangle you, will you please
get rid of the corn rows?
내가 끼인 것 풀러주면 그 머리 풀을래?
I guess so.
그럴께
Some of these look a little frayed.
머리가 좀 닳은 것 같은데?
Yeah, I tried to gnaw myself free.
좀 바둥거렸었어
Hey / Hi
안녕
So did you, uh, did you tell Ross?
로스한테 얘기했어?
Well, I tried
하려고 했었는데
but then he had a shampoo related emergency.
샴푸때문에 응급상황이 생겨버렸어
Huh, so I guess now it's your turn again.
그러니까 이제 다시 니 차례야
No, no, no,....I think it's better
if you tell him. You know?
안돼 니가 말하는게 나을 것 같애
여자가 하는게 나을 것 같거든
And it's easier for a woman. That way,
로스가 화내면 이러면 되잖아..
you know, if he gets mad,
all you have to do is go
"I didn't mean it."
"일부러 그런건 아니었어"
"정~말 미안해"
I'm so sorry.
Yeah, cause that's what we do.
그래.. 여자들이 다 그러지..
Alright, alright, okay, um,
how about this? How about this?
그럼 이렇게 하자
Tomorrow,
내일 둘이 같이 가서 같이 얘기하는 거야
tomorrow we both go and will tell him together.
Okay, that sounds fair.
그래 그게 좋겠어
That just means, once again, we can't ...
난 그냥 다시
I know, I know. That's okay.
알아 안다구
우린 자제할 수 있어 동물이 아니니깐
I mean we can control ourselves.
We're not animals. / No!
물론 기다릴 수 있지
Of course we can wait.
Alright, so I guess that means good night, then.
그럼 그만 자야겠네
그래 잘자
Yup. Good night.
Good~ night.
자알 자~
Good night.
잘자
정말로 잘자
Seriously, good night.
그만해
Stop saying good night.
Okay!
알았어
I'm so sorry.
정~말 미안해
[ 해 석] 윤미내(minaii@hotmail.net)
[ 싱 크 ] 변정주(jungjoo@kaist.ac.kr)
[ 테스터 ] 김종옥(joscool76@korea.com)
Look what I found in the drawer.
내가 옷장에서 뭘 찾았게
And you said I would never wear this.
이거 안쓴다고 구박했었지?
Now that I entangled you,
how about you do a little something for me?
내가 자기 구해줬으니까
나한테도 뭐하나 해주라?
Sure. What do you have in mind?
그래 뭔데?
알면서
I think you know.
그래?
Really? I don't, I don't really feel like it.
별로 안내키는데
이게 내가 바라는 거야
This is what I want to do.
Okay.
그게 왜 그렇게 좋은지 이해가 안돼
I just don't get why you like it so much.
She's an FBI agent posing as a beauty contestant!
FBI요원이 미스코리아인척 하고 있다니까!
THANK YOU. I APPRECIATE YOUR FEEDBACK.
- Kevin Kim